玄黄端现 太极混沌如鸡蛋
ln the beginning, there was darkness...
随着轰的一声
and then, bang...
诞生了无限膨胀的
giving birth to an endless expanding existence...
时间 空间和物质
of time, space, and matter.
现在所见超乎我们的想象
Now, see further than we've ever imagined...
超越了客观认知极限
beyond the limits of our existence...
那地方我们称之为"宇宙"
in a place we call "The Universe."
从一开始
From our beginnings...
人类就力图拓展自己的领域
the human race has endeavored to extend our reach.
现在我们在走向最后的边界
And nowwe're headed for the final frontier.
我们该是两星物种
We should be a two-planet species.
从月球上的前哨站到火星上成熟的殖民地
From an outpost on the Moon to a full-fledged colony on Mars.
那会是个挑战
lt could be a challenge.
同时也会是个灾难
lt could also be a disaster.
目前 我们在打造搭载我们的火箭
Right now, we're building the rockets to get us there...
以及生存所需的装备
and the machines we'll need to survive.
你拥有当太空人的"料"吗？
Do you have the right stuff to join the crew?
我想要两个Scotty和两个Spocks (星际迷航)
l want two Scottys and two Spocks.
倒计时已经开始
The countdown begins now.
"宇宙:太空殖民"
"The Universe: Colonizing Space."
--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://cmct.cc
影片压制:春树  字幕来源:五羊皮  调校:御雪寒狼  招募Q号:76846146
[历史频道] 第二季 第十三集 殖民太空
[History Channel] The UniverseⅡ 13of19 Colonizing.Space
殖民太空已不再是科幻小说里的东西
Colonizing space is no longer the stuff of science fiction.
貌似将生活在另一个世界里的第一批人类
lt's likely the first humans who will live on anotherworld...
已经诞生在了地球上
have already been born on Earth.
对于这些开拓者来说 这种冒险就会是
For these pioneers, this adventure will be...
终极宇宙野营
the ultimate cosmic camping trip.
你须带上你需要带上的所有东西
You need to bring everything you need with you.
你须带上居所
You need to bring a place to live.
你须带上吃的
You need to bring food you're going to eat.
你须带上喝的水
You need to bring the water you need to drink.
在地球上 至少你无须带上呼吸的空气
Now on Earth, at least...you don't need to bring the air you breathe...
然而 一旦进入太空 我们同样必须带上它
but when we go into space, we'll need to bring that, too.
我们必须随身携带所有东西
Everything we need has got to be with us.
如果丢了什么 坏了什么
lf something's missing or if something breaks...
那将会大难临头
it could be a disaster.
我们需要带上用得到的每一样东西
We need to have everything we're going to use with us.
我们需要使其发挥作用
We need to have it working.
成功的太空殖民将取决于它
The success of space colonization will depend upon it.
去外头安家的野心
The ambitions to settle somewhere out there...
直击我们生存的核心
go right to the core of our existence.
殖民太空无法抗拒的理由
The compelling reasons to colonize space...
就是看我们能否将活动范围拓展到地球以外
are to see if we can expand the range of our activities beyond the Earth...
还是我们真的被局限在了地球上
or are we really confined to the Earth?
我认为那是我们需要得到答案的重大问题
l think that's an important question...we need to know the answer to.
第二个问题是 生活的作用是什么
The second one is, what's the role of life?
我们在地球上管这种现象叫生活
We have on this Earth a phenomenon called life.
是否注定要拓展到地球以外去呢？
ls it destined to spread beyond the Earth?
我们是可以使其拓展的物种
We are the species that can cause that spread.
卡尔·萨根 著名天文学家
Carl Sagan, the great noted astronomer...
曾说过 我们该是两星物种
once said that we should be a two-planet species.
也就是说 我们应该殖民一个星球
That is, we should colonize one planet...
同时还拥有地球 因为 比如
and also have the Earth because, for example...
地球身处宇宙射击场中央
the Earth is in the middle of a cosmic shooting gallery.
彗星 流星四处乱窜
There are comets and meteors whizzing all over the place...
千百年乃至数百万年来从未停止过
on a scale of hundreds to thousands and millions ofyears...
我们需要一个备用的行星
and we need a spare planet...
因为 将所有的生命只放在一个星球上
because it's simply too precious to put all life...
实在是太珍贵了
on simply one planet.
在广袤的太空中
ln the vastness of space...
有一个目的地脱颖而出
there's one destination above all others...
是杰出的殖民首选之地
that stands out as prime real estate for colonization.
火星是太阳系的大奖
Mars is the grand prize of the solar system.
它是人类可以定居的最近的行星
lt's the closest planet which human beings can settle.
这颗最近的行星拥有生命和文明所有必需的资源
lt's the closest planet that has all the resources needed...for life and civilization.
火星 太阳的第四颗行星
Mars, the fourth planet from the Sun.
它约地球的一半大
lt's about half the size of Earth...
其与地球的最短距离约3500万英里
and, at its closest pass, is roughly 35 million miles away.
古罗马人将其红色与战争联系在一起
The ancient Romans associated its red colorwith hostility...
将其命名为战神
and named it after their god ofwar.
然而 非但没有敌意 火星还是继地球之后
But farfrom hostile, Mars has the potential...
潜在的最友好的行星
to be the most hospitable planet after the Earth.
气态外行星没有踏脚之地
The gaseous outer planets offer no solid ground.
在内行星中
Among the inner planets...
水星太靠近太阳 酷热难当
Mercury is too scorchingly close to the Sun...
金星 尽管大小如地球
and Venus, though similar to Earth in size...
因为失控的温室效应 受到华氏870度的煎熬
is baked to 870 degrees Fahrenheit...by a runaway green house effect.
同时 其大气压力将压碎所有想成为移民的人类
lt also has an atmospheric pressure...that would crush any would-be human settlers.
火星也有自己的缺陷
Mars does have its own pitfalls.
实际上它的气压极低
lt actually has extremely low atmospheric pressure...
会造成你血液沸腾 然后冻结
which would cause your blood to boil and then freeze.
但是增压太空服可以克服那个危险
But a pressurized spacesuit can overcome that danger.
虽然 火星很冷
And while it's cold on Mars...
典型的白昼温度在零下20到40度
with typical daytime temperatures 20 to 40 degrees below zero...
但是人类穿着适当的防护 不难生存下去
humans could easily survive, wearing proper protection.
关键在于 这颗红色星球
Most important, the Red Planet...
具有稠密的二氧化碳大气
with its carbon dioxide-rich atmosphere...
似乎具有我们维持殖民地运行所必需的自然资源
seems to have the natural resources we would need...to keep a colony running.
在火星上 我们有了二氧化碳就可以提取氧气
On Mars, we have carbon dioxide from which we can extract oxygen...
制成燃料
and make fuels from it.
大气层里有水蒸汽
There's watervapor in the atmosphere...
同时也存在于极地冰盖中
and also in the polar caps.
火星上的土壤 表土
The soil on Mars, the regolith...
含有矿物质和各种化合物
has the minerals and various compounds we need...
以供我们在火星上建立殖民地
in order to set up a colony on Mars.
如今的火星是个不毛之地
Today Mars is a frozen desert.
然而空间探测器拍摄的照片显示出侵蚀明显证据
But photos taken by space probes show clear evidence of erosion.
这意味着 火星表面不仅曾经有过水
This means that not only did Mars at one time...have water on its surface...
而且有可能曾经维持过生命
but also that it may have once supported life.
寻找生命存在过的证据 即使是微生物
Finding evidence of previous life, even microscopic organisms...
都有可能在建立短期基地
might make the difference between whetherwe establish...
和较为长久的殖民地之间产生差异
a short-term base or a more permanent colony there.
长期使命计划已摆上了航天局的日程
Long-range mission planning is already underway at NASA.
航天局计划到2020年人类重返月球
The space agency plans to return man to the Moon by 2020...
作为火星任务的跳板
as a steppingstone to a Mars mission.
月球探索的一个重大主题是前往火星
One of the major themes for the lunar exploration...is called "Forward to Mars."
在那个主题中 我们将不断思考
And within that theme, we'll be constantly thinking...
我们将如何去玩转火星
about howwe will operate on Mars.
宇航员将参与研究
The astronauts will be involved with studying...
人类将如何回应行星环境
how humans react to the planetary environment...
他们的工作会有多艰苦 需要睡上多久
how hard they can work, how much sleep they need...
他们需要多少消遣
how much entertainment they need...
他们将如何协调任务管理
how they will relate to mission control.
我们必须学会处理所有这些
We need to learn to deal with all of these issues...
人们生活在深远环境中随之而来的问题
that come with people living in far-reaching environments.
准备长期荒野之行的重要一步
An important step in preparing for a long wilderness trip...
就是测试装备 在本地筹备一切
is testing the gear, setting up everything in a local spot...
甚至 就在你自己的后院
even in your backyard.
确保你准备了所需的一切和有效可靠
Make sure you've got everything you need and it all works.
同样 在月球上建立基地
ln that same way, setting up a base on the Moon...
是为了在火星上建立基地的一个操练
is a practice run for setting up a base on Mars.
我们学习要做的事
We learn what to do.
我们学习掌握所有必需的设备的操控
We learn all the equipment we need and how it works.
我们要让一切都工作恰到好处
We get everything working just right.
所谓的一切 包括了多功能机器人
"Everything" includes versatile robotic machines...
比如"ATHLETE"
like "ATHLETE," which stands...
是全地形六肢外星探测器的缩写
forAll-Terrain Hex-Limbed Extraterrestrial Explorer.
ATHLETE的目的是在月球或火星上运输
ATHLETE is designed to carry cargo on the Moon or Mars.
我们要带的最重要的货物将会是居所
The most important cargo we could carry would be a habitat.
那通常是所有人类使团所携带的最大物件
That's usually the largest single piece of any human mission.
然而 ATHLETE能做的远不止运货
But ATHLETE can do much more thanjust haul cargo.
机器的每一面都装备有高清相机
Each side of the machine...is equipped with high-definition cameras...
具有360度的广角
that give a 360-degree view of the surroundings...
呈现给星球上或轨道舱里的操作员
and display it to an operator...based either on the planet, in an orbiting spacecraft...
或发回地球
or back on Earth.
每一条腿就像是自展式瑞士军刀
And each limb is like its own self-deploying Swiss Army knife.
它能做的一件事情是它用自己的一条腿
One of the things it can do is take one of its limbs...
从工具套里取出工具
and grab a tool out of a tool holster...
并利用工具进行挖掘
and use that tool to excavate.
所以 我们会装上铲子 钻头 钳子等工具
So we have built scoops and drills and grippers and other tools.
最有趣的一件事
One of the most interesting things...
就是一旦ATHLETE的一条腿出故障
is that if a leg were to fail on ATHLETE...
那么邻近的两条腿事实上就会抓取工具
the two adjacent legs could, in fact, grab tools...
拆除那条出故障的腿
and disconnect the one leg that's failed...
进行截肢 将其丢在地上
and amputate it and leave it on the surface.
用上了ATHLETE这样的设备
With equipment like ATHLETE...
宇航员就有可能在月球上建立起长期基地
astronauts will be able to establish a long-term base on the Moon
测试他们如何做到自给自足
and test how self-sufficient they can be.
只有这样 按照航天局的说法
Only then, according to NASA...
我们才能真正知道我们是否已经为前往火星做好了准备
will we really know if we're ready to go to Mars.
我们对在太空生活情况考量的真正严峻考验
The real acid test of our understanding of how to live in space...
将是送上一组队员 比如说 6个人
will be to take a crew of, say, six people...
将他们放在月球的背面
put them on the far side of the Moon...
看不到地球的地方
where they cannot see the Earth...
会产生无法联系上地球的心理劣势
and have the psychological disadvantage...of not being able to connect to the Earth...
来观察他们能否利用我们为其设计的系统
and see if they can exist for a year on their own...
靠他们自己生存一年
with the systems that we design for them.
如果我们能够做上这样的测试和实验
lfwe're able to actually do that kind of a test and experiment...
那么 我认为我们就可以按章照抄了 也就是说
then l think we will have checked the box that, yes...
我们准备就绪 进入太阳系
we're ready to move out into the solar system...
安排更为困难的组织方法 诸如去火星
and settle more difficult regimes, such as the planet Mars.
月球靠近地球
The Moon's close proximity to Earth...
约24万英里 只要3天的行程
about 240,000 miles, only a three-day trip...
是个合适的试验场
makes it a convenient proving ground.
然而 其环境与火星完全迥异
But its environment is vastly different from Mars.
火星与月球相比
Mars compares to the Moon...
就好像是人类探索的早年时期的北美与格陵兰相比
as North America compared to Greenland...in the previous age of human exploration.
我的意思是 格陵兰比较靠近欧洲
l mean, Greenland was closer to Europe.
欧洲人最先到达那里
Europeans got there first...
然而最终 其环境太差劲了
but, ultimately, it was too poor an environment...
不利于人类文明的新分支去开发它
for a new branch of human civilization to really develop it.
月球也一样
Same with the Moon.
月球靠近地球
The Moon is closer to the Earth.
我们最先到达了那里
We got there first.
但是 作为安身之地 火星要强多了
But as a place for settlement, Mars is a much better place to go.
火星的水和其它有用的自然资源要多于月球
Mars has more water and other useful natural resources...
它同时具有地球这样的昼夜循环
lt also has an Earthlike day/night cycle...than the Moon.
只比我们这里多出40分钟
that lasts only about forty minutes longer than ours.
那就是为什么火星协会
That's why the Mars Society...
科学家 研究员以及航天局工作人员的一个组织
an organization of scientists, researchers, and NASA personnel...
认为我们应该完全跳过月球
thinks we should skip the Moon entirely...
直奔那颗红色星球
and head directly for a rendezvous with the Red Planet.
"直奔火星"是一项将人送上火星的计划
Mars Direct is a plan for sending humans to Mars...
它无需非传统的科幻飞船
without the need forfuturistic, science-fiction spacecraft...
无需月球基地
and without the need for a lunar base.
直奔火星计划打算两次升空
The Mars Direct mission plan proposes two launches.
首先将地球返回舱(ERV)送往火星
The first sends an Earth return vehicle, or ERV, to Mars.
使其登陆火星 然后打开泵
Land this on Mars, and then you run a pump...
抽取火星空气 其主要成分是二氧化碳
and you suck in the Martian air, which is mostly carbon dioxide.
我们将二氧化碳和我们从地球
And we react that carbon dioxide with a little bit of hydrogen...
带去的一点点氢进行反应
that we brought with us from Earth...
生产大量的甲烷
to produce a large supply of methane...
氧气火箭推进剂
an oxygen rocket propellant.
这样我们就给地球返回舱加满了燃料
So nowwe got a fully fueled-Up Earth return vehicle...
在火星表面等着我们
sitting, waiting for us on the surface of Mars.
第二次发射是将太空人居住舱送上火星
The second launch sends a crew habitat module to Mars.
在完成了火星上的任务后
After conducting their mission on the Red Planet...
宇航员就登上地球返回舱回家
the astronauts board the ERV to return home...
留下居住舱
and leave behind the habitat module.
每一次后
Each time we do this...
我们都会在基地增加一座居住舱
we add another hab module to the base.
几次任务以后 我们就建起了新世界
And after a few missions, we've built the beginning...
首个人类定居点
of the first human settlement on a newworld.
这方面不存在任何技术问题
There is nothing in this that is beyond our technology.
只是一个有没有一点勇气和有没有一点意志的问题
lt's simply a question of having a little bit of moxie, a little bit of will.
但是 对于怀疑者来说 直奔火星计划是异想天开
But to skeptics, the Mars Direct mission plan is a non-starter.
如果我们想直奔火星
lfwe tried to go to Mars directly...
第一步将会是诸如20年的准备和测试
the first step would be something like...twenty years of preparation and testing.
对此 老百姓将会对前往火星的想法十分反感
And at that point, the public will get very bored...with the idea of going to Mars.
我们认为在我们去月球的时段里
We believe that we can get to the Moon...
老百姓会踊跃参与人类的太空探索
in a timeframe where the public will be heavily engaged...
那也会让我们前往火星
in human exploration of space, and that will enable us...
某种意义上 会更快些
to get to Mars, in some sense, faster...
因为我们会更有信心
because we'll have more confidence...
对人的生命的风险会更少些
and we'll have less risk to human life.
前往火星 无论是直接前往
Getting to Mars, whether by direct mission...
还是在进一步的月球探索之后
or only after further lunar exploration...
都只是迈向殖民行星的第一步
is just the first step towards colonizing the planet.
抵达那里将会伴随着生活的挑战
But getting there will be as challenging as living there.
旅程的生存将会是人类耐力的终极考验
Surviving thejourneywill be the ultimate test of human endurance.
火星之旅要六个月的时间
The trip to Mars is six months long.
那是当地球与火星处于最短的直线距离上
That's when the Earth and Mars are at their closest alignment...
是最佳出发时间
making it the best time to depart.
地球与火星都围绕着太阳转
Earth and Mars both go around the Sun...
但是两者的运转速度不同
but they go around at different rates.
每隔两年 地球与火星会处于太阳的同一侧
And every two years, Earth and Mars...are on the same side of the Sun...
于是 只有两者接近时
and so then, that's when it's close...
才只需要6个月抵达那里
and then it only takes six months to get there.
一旦地球与火星分别处于太阳的两侧时 算了吧
When Earth and Mars are on opposite sides of the Sun, forget it.
你不会从一颗行星到另一颗行星的
You're not going from one planet to another...
我们还没有那样的技术
not with the technologies we've got.
我们必须等待翘曲飞行那样的东西
You've got to wait forwarp drive for something like that.
需要开发出新的硬件
There are new hardware elements that need to be developed...
以使人类飞往火星
to enable a human flight mission to Mars...
并没有什么新技术
but no new technology.
我们需要做出所有的东西 我们知道如何去做
Everything we need to make, we know how to make.
我们现在将人类送上火星的能力远超过
We are much closer today to being able to send humans to Mars...
1961年 肯尼迪启动的将人类送上月球
than we were to being able to send men to the Moon...
的月球计划时的能力
in 1961, when Kennedy started the Moon program.
我们是在8年后才到了那里
And we were there eight years later.
零 点火
Zero. All engines running.
新硬件将包括战神
The new hardware will include the Ares...
新一代火箭
the next-generation rocket...
将把人类送上月球甚至更远
that will launch man to the Moon and beyond.
战神应该会在10年内发射升空
The Ares should be ready for liftoffwithin a decade.
其大小如负有盛名的阿波罗任务中的土星5号
lt's about the size of the Saturn V ofApollo fame.
身高超过36层楼高 土星5号
Taller than a thirty-six-story building, the Saturn V...
曾是史上最大最强的火箭
was the largest and most powerful rocket ever launched...
能将53吨有效载荷送入月球轨道
capable of delivering a 53-ton payload into lunar orbit.
然而战神 利用航天飞机衍生的推进器
But the Ares, using boosters derived from the space shuttle...
每次月球之旅能够多运送22吨货物
will be able to muscle an extra twenty-two tons of cargo...on each trip to the Moon.
所以 如果你有了很大的火箭
So, if you have very large rockets...
那么你就能少几次发射
you can have fewer launches in order to assemble...
组装起去火星的飞船
the spacecraft that goes to Mars.
大火箭确实是我们渴求的产物
The large rocket is really a product of the desire...
为了最终关注我们探索方案中的火星
to ultimately look at Mars in our exploration scenarios.
新硬件还包括猎户座 载人航天器
New hardware will also include Orion, the crewvehicle.
其体积将是阿波罗航天舱的两倍半还多
lt will be more than two and a half times the volume...of an Apollo capsule.
在执行登陆月球任务时 猎户座将与
On its missions to the Moon, Orion will dock with a lunar lander...
一个单独发射到太空中的月球着陆器会合
sent into space on a separate launch.
不同于阿波罗飞船
Unlike Apollo's spacecraft...
猎户座在月球探测期间会自动围绕月球运转
Orion will orbit the Moon unmanned while lunar explorations take place.
宇航员会再度与猎户座会合一起返回地球
The astronauts will re-dock with Orion for the return to Earth.
这个新载人航天器将借鉴太空站的许多硬件
This new crewvehicle will borrow much of its hardware...from the space station.
这里是前景在握之地
And this is a place where the future is caught, so.
1997年前 宇航员杰瑞·里宁哲在俄罗斯和平号空间站上
ln 1997, retired astronaut Jerry Linenger spent about five months...
度过了5个月左右的时间
nearly the length oftime it would take to get to Mars...
几乎相当于抵达火星的时间长度
aboard the Russian space station Mir.
在执行长期任务期间 他克服了许多艰险
While on the long mission, he overcame many dangers...
包括轨道航天器上有史以来最严重的火灾
including the most severe fire ever on an orbiting spacecraft.
化学品泄漏引发了大火 持续了90秒钟
A chemical leak ignited a blaze that lasted ninety seconds...
威胁到了机组
threatening the crew.
我认为基本上能挽救我们生命的东西
The things that l think pretty much saved our lives...
就是这些氧气呼吸器
are these oxygen breathing devices...
火警中 当然必须要快速开启
and during the fire, of course, that had to go on quickly.
要是谁直接掌握了硬件
lf anybody knows firsthand how the hardware...
包括生命支持系统
including life support systems...
那么能坚持在载人火星飞船上的人 就非他莫属了
will work on the spacecraft taking man to Mars, it's him.
在地球上这一切都是不以为然的事情
Down here on Earth, you take so much for granted.
要知道 我们在户外
You know, we're out here...
阳光和新鲜空气围着你
the sunshine, the fresh air all around you.
要知道在太空中你不得不制造出来
You know, in space, you have to make it.
你必须制氧
You've got to make the oxygen.
在上面你身处一个封闭的生态系统
Up there, you're in a closed ecosystem.
你必须尽量循环利用
You have to recycle, you know, whatever you can.
厕所在这边 设计极其简单
And the toilet itself is over this way...and it's a very simple design.
比如 小解 尿液收集
For example, we'd take the urine, collect it...
是利用一个小漏斗 小抽吸装置
using a little funnel, little suction device.
不管男女都撒尿在这个管子里
For the male orfemale urination is this tube here.
我们会收集起来 将尿液转化成水
We'd collect that up, we'd convert the urine into water...
水再变成氧 我们会呼吸空间站上的
water to oxygen, and we would breathe our urine...
封闭生态系统里的尿
inside that closed ecosystem of the space station.
我希望大家对我们带你飞过时
l hope you've got a feel for the space station...
对空间站有个感性认识
as we flewyou through it.
新硬件还能提供清洁可靠的能源
New hardware will also provide power from clean, reliable sources.
我们会保护红色星球的
We're going green to the Red Planet.
太阳能电池板在重返月球时会发挥作用
Solar panels will do thejob on the return to the Moon...
然而在去火星的长途旅行中
but the longerjourney to Mars...
就需要另一种能源了
will require another power source.
在我们启程去火星时 远离太阳
As we get off to Mars, the solar insulation...
火星上的阳光强度只有地球上的一半
the intensity of sunlight at Mars is only about half that at the Earth...
所以 太阳能电池板效率不高
so solar panels are less effective.
我们可能要认真考虑在某些飞船上用上核能
We may have to think carefully about using nuclear power sources...in some of these spacecraft...
事实上 人们正在认真思考月球上利用核能
and, in fact, people are thinking seriously...about nuclear power sources on the surface of the Moon...
以解决长久的能源 而不必担心在月球的黑暗期间
in order to generate long-term power and not have to worry...about the periods of darkness on the Moon...
因没有阳光而不得不携带蓄电池
where you don't have sunlight...and you have to bring batteries up to store power.
尽管用上了所有的新硬件 火星之旅
But despite all the new hardware, thejourney to Mars...
依然充满着潜在的风险
will still have its share of potential hazards...
就如同涉足任何一个陌生的地方
just like any trek to an unfamiliar place.
设想你去野外露营 远离家门
lmagine you're on a wilderness camping trip...
远离你熟悉的环境
the familiar surroundings that you're used to. and you leave home...
你踏上了长途之旅
You go out on a long trip.
潜在的风险 危险:
Potential dangers, hazards:
塌方 雪崩 迷路
Rock slides, avalanches, getting lost...
装备坏了 会出现各种各样的问题
equipment breakdown, all sorts of possible problems.
但是你还是会义无反顾 勇往直前
But you want to go anyway.
准备 出发
You prepare, you go out.
会是一场冒险
lt could be an adventure.
会是一场灾难
lt could be a disaster.
前往月球和火星 同样如此
Going to the Moon and Mars is going to be like that, too.
你离开了熟悉的地球环境
You leave the familiar surroundings of Earth...
进入太空
you go out in space...
潜在的问题 情况 设备故障
potential problems, issues, equipment breakdown...
你在野营中可能碰到的许多类似的问题
many of the same kind of problems...that you might have on a camping trip...
宇航员在火星上也可能会碰上
the astronauts might face on Mars.
那会是一场挑战
lt could be a challenge.
也会是一场灾难
lt could also be a disaster.
宇航员会遭遇的主要危险
A major hazard the crewwill encounter...
将是零重力环境中的长期失重
will be prolonged weightlessness in the zero-gravity environment.
毫不费力 乔治
Easy in, Georgie.
噢 是啊 真的
Oh, yes, it's true.
解除了平日的荷载
Relieved of bearing its usual load...
人体骨骼开始恶化
the human skeleton starts to deteriorate.
磷酸钙流失
There's a loss of calcium phosphate...
那是骨强度关键的化学物质
a chemical critical to the rigidity of bones...
骨细胞数量会减少
and the number of bone cells actually decreases.
一天24小时的漂浮
For twenty-four hours a day, you're floating...
使得你的身体会在生理上聪明地适应新的环境
and your body very smartly starts physiologically to adapt...to that new circumstance.
因此 为了对付这一情况 努力保持你的强度
So, in order to counter that, try to keep your strength up...
我会用上跑步机
l'd get on a treadmill.
每天两次一小时时间
Two one-hour periods a day...
让全身振奋起来
it's about all you can muster up there.
尽管那样 回来时只能达到升空前强度水平的65%
ln spite of that, you know, came back at about sixty-five percent...of my pre-flight strength level.
大量肌肉萎缩
A lot of muscle atrophy...
尤为关键的是 有约14%的骨质流失
and, more significantly, about a fourteen percent bone loss.
告诉你 下半身
You know, hips, lower spine.
到了太空中 漂浮不费吹灰之力
You get up in space, you're floating effortlessly...
骨骼不停地流失钙
the bone just keeps dumping calcium...
那可能是长期飞行中的捣乱分子
and that could be a showstopper on a long-duration flight.
在回到地面后 唯有经过剧烈的体能训练
lt was only through intense physical training...after his return to Earth...
才可以将骨质流失从14%减到2%
that Linengerwas able to reduce his bone loss...from fourteen percent to two percent.
失重的体虚效应
The debilitating effects ofweightlessness...
在我们踏足乃至殖民火星之前
remain an issue that must be addressed...
依然是一个必须克服的问题
before we set foot on Mars, let alone colonize it.
继续在研究解决之道
Research continues on a possible solution.
很多人期待着人造重力
A lot of people have looked towards artificial gravity...
意思是飞船一路盘旋而上
which means you spin the spacecraft up...
最终将获得重力
and you end up with a gravity...
就像是帮助给你的骨骼加载
and that would sort of help load your bones...
因为在失重的情况下
because when you're in weightlessness...
你的血液在流动 骨骼没有了荷载
your fluids are shifting, your bones are unloaded...
你每个月会损失2%的骨质
and you lose about two percent ofyour bone mass per month.
那将是个很大的障碍
lt would be a large hurdle...
因为为了让宇航员抵达火星时健健康康
because in order for crews to be healthy when they arrive on Mars...
就需要在整个航程中得到锻炼
they need to be strong for the entire trip.
之前从未有人建造过旋转飞船
Nobody's ever built a rotating spacecraft before...
因此 谁都不想成为第一人
so nobody wants to be the first person.
然而多数人相信利用旋转飞船产生的人造重力
But most people believe that some kind of artificial gravity...
前往火星
with a rotating spacecraft on the way to Mars...
不失为履行使命的方法
is actually the way to do the mission.
火星之旅还面临着太阳风的危害
Missions headed for Mars also face dangerfrom solar storms.
太阳释放出的高能粒子爆发
High-energy particle bursts unleashed from the Sun...
会将毫无防备的宇航员命丧九泉
could wipe out a crew ifthey aren't prepared for the onslaught.
所以说辐射是一个不小的捣乱分子
So radiation is one of the larger showstoppers...
从技术上说
in terms of technology...
必须开发出未来的航天器
that needs to be developed for a future vehicle.
最简单的处理方法就是制造一所风暴庇护所
The easiest way to deal with that is just to make a storm shelter...
这样 一旦你预测到太阳风暴来临了
so that if you can somehow predict...when the solar storms are approaching...
那是你可以通过导航卫星从地球获悉的
which you would do with various navigation satellites...and relaying them from Earth...
于是 你可以躲进庇护所 等其过去后
then you could get into the shelter and wait it out...
再回到飞船里
and then be able to go back into the spacecraft.
然后 火星上也一样
And then similarly on Mars...
一旦你获悉风暴将来临
when you know that there's a storm coming...
你也可以躲进庇护所
you would go into a shelter.
光旅程就让殖民火星成为史无前例的挑战
Thejourney alone will make colonizing Mars...an unprecedented challenge...
但是巨大的风险将换来历史性的回报
but the enormous risks come with historic rewards.
不作决定比让谁去尤为重要
No decision is more important than who gets to go.
认为你更称职当一名太空先驱吗？
Think you have what it takes to be a space pioneer?
排队等候
Get in line.
已有人在接受训练了
There are people already training for thejob.
殖民火星将需要特殊的人种
Colonizing Mars will require a special breed of people.
由于任务可能要持续两年多
With missions that could last more than two years...
遴选行星先驱的合格人选
selecting those with the right stuff to be planetary pioneers...
是成功的关键所在
will be critical to the success.
2 1 点火
Two, one, we have ignition.
发射成本以数十亿计
The cost of a launch, in the billions of dollars...
紧凑的航天器舱位
and the tight quarters of the spacecraft...
将要求机组成员降低到最少
will keep the number of crew people to a bare minimum.
我认为人数是四个
l believe that number is four.
那是你可以发送的最少人数
lt's the smallest number you can send...
把机组分成两组
and divide the crew up into two groups...
没人是单独的
and have no one be alone.
那是你发送的最少人数
And it's the smallest number that you can send...
其中需要有两种完成任务的主要技能
in which you have the two primary skills...
两者相得益彰
of the mission, both multiply backed up.
其中一组要包括两位机械能手
A crew of that size would consist of two ace mechanics...
会修理任何东西 这样才能挽救生命
who can fix anything, and in doing so, save lives.
另外还有两名专业科学家
Joining them would be the two field scientists...
智力荷载
the intellectual payload.
所以 按《星际迷航》的术语
So, in "Star Trek" terminology,
我想要两个Scotty和两个Spock
l want two Scottys and two Spocks.
火星殖民者需要的不仅仅是这些重要的技能
Mars colonists will need more than just these vital skill sets.
他们还需要意志坚定
They also need to be mentally tough.
人们认为宇航员很顽强
People think that astronauts are tough...
他们只会永远服从命令 执行计划
they will just always obey commands...and will operate according to plan...
但是 他们也是人
but they are human...
人在这种情况下
and humans in these situations...
确实会产生怪异的心理反应
do develop strange psychological reactions.
我们确实必须有所掌握
We really have to understand that...
因为 那是宇航员挑选过程的一部分
because that's part of the crew selection process.
好 我要飞进节点了
All right, l'm going to fly into the node.
宇航员必须适应太空舱或密封舱狭小的空间
Astronauts will have to adapt to the confined space...of the crewvehicle or habitat.
如果你患有幽闭恐怖症 就算了吧
If you're claustrophobic, forget it.
事实上 我们要测试的
We actually test for that.
我们会将你塞进一个球状物里
We put you in sort of a ball, zip it up...
里面一片漆黑 你就塞在里面
it's totally dark, you're crammed in the thing.
在睡舱里 有一个小窗户
lnside the sleep cabin, there's also a little window...
睡袋就放在里面
sleeping bag sitting right here.
这就是指挥员睡舱的情形
This just happens to be the commander's sleep station.
他们会给你安上心脏监护器
And they have heart monitors on you.
我当时睡着了
ln my case, l fell asleep.
他们最后打开舱门 说 你不错
They finally came, opened the thing up, and said, "You're fine."
但是 如果你在密封空间里睡不着觉的话
But if you don't fall asleep in a closed space...
你就不是合格人选
you're not the right person.
作为唯一的生命形式应对一个毫无生机的星球
Dealing with being the only life forms...on an otherwise lifeless planet...
那将是另一大心理挑战
will be another major psychological challenge.
到了外太空 你真的被人类开除了
Out there in space, you truly are just removed from mankind.
要知道 我们生活中的交流
And, you know, the interactions we have in life...
同事 亲朋好友之间
with the colleagues, friends, family...
是你视为理所当然的
youjust sort of take it for granted down here...
但是 到了上面 突然之间
but up there, all of a sudden...
那种孤独是我从未感觉过的
it is isolation like l've neverfelt before.
要是你不自我感觉良好的话
lfyou're not totally comfortable with yourself...
你将会在那里度日如年
you're going to have some very, very difficult times up there.
四个月了
lt's been four months...
四个月 模拟火星任务
four months, simulated Mars mission.
大家都表现出色
Everyone's doing great.
为了培训执行这个极端任务的人
To train people for this extreme mission...
火星协会建立了两个火星模拟研究站
the Mars Society has built two Mars analog research stations...
来实践模拟任务
to practice simulated missions.
6人组成的小组
Crews consisting of as many as six people...
大部分是大学里的科学家和航天局的工作人员
mostly university scientists and NASA personnel...
他们的工作条件基本上如同
operate under many of the same constraints...
宇航员在火星上坚持的
that astronauts will endure on Mars.
他们出门就穿上航天服
They don't go outside without wearing spacesuits.
他们以火星时间作息 比地球昼夜要长出37分钟
They live on Martian time, 37 minutes longer than an Earth day.
与丹佛指挥中心的通讯
Their communication with mission control in Denver...
有20分钟的延迟
is on a twenty-minute delay to simulate the time it takes...
以模拟无线电信号从火星到地球的时间
for a radio signal to go from Mars to Earth.
可能最具挑战的是
Maybe most challenging...
他们必须共处在最小人居空间内
they must coexist in a habitat with minimal personal space.
这样做 你就可以发现火星上什么行 什么不行
By doing that, you find out what works on Mars and what doesn't...
技能组合的类型
and what kind of a skill mix...
所需的组员特质组合
what character mix you need in the crew...
哪些技术对组员最有用
what technologies are likely to be most useful to the crew...
如何组织组员 谁可以担任指挥员
how to organize the crew, who should command the crew...
如何紧凑地分配水源
how tight you can ration the water...
在开展这类工作时如何保持士气
and still sustain morale while you're doing this kind ofwork.
这不像登月任务 只有一个星期的时间
This is not like a lunar mission, which only lasts a week...
你可以组织三个试飞员 他们面临的情况是
where you can get three test pilots, and they canjust suck up the fact...
他们在整个时间段里不必相互喜欢 相互融洽
that they don't really like each other for that duration time and get along.
小组首先去沙漠研究站
Crews first go to the desert research station...
位于犹他州汉克斯维尔
located outside Hanksville, Utah...
执行短期任务 为期两个星期
to conduct short-term missions, lasting two weeks.
期间 他们会执行舱外活动
During that time, they perform EVAs, extra-vehicular activities...
诸如搜集土壤样本供地质研究
such as collecting soil samples for geological study.
在沙漠工作完成后
After completing their desert work...
小组准备参加为期4个月的长期任务
the crews are ready tojoin longer missions...
位于加拿大北极地区德文岛的研究站
lasting up to four months at the research station on Devon lsland...in the Canadian Arctic.
德文岛是进行火星研究的一个关键地方
Devon lsland is one of the key places...
因为它与世隔绝
that you can conduct Mars research because of its isolation.
它是世界上最大的无人居住的岛屿
lt's the largest uninhabited island in the world.
周围没有生命迹象
There are no signs of life around...
岩石上会有一些细菌和藻类生长
maybe some bacteria and algae growing on the rocks...
还有因为有火山口构造
and also because the craterformation...
研究站就位于类似于在其它行星上
that the research station is located on is similar to a crater...
可以看到的典型的火山口
that you would typically find on any planet.
北极有大量的永久冻土层
There's a lot of permafrost up in the Arctic...
在那里 钻探寻找微生物
and drilling into there, looking for microbial life...
所做的实验会类似于火星表面
could be a similar experiment...to what you would do on the surface of Mars.
我们进行辐射站 气象站的舱外活动
We're going on our radiation/weather station EVA.
我们会获取四周的读数
We'll be taking readings of the surrounding area.
除了进行实地研究外
ln addition to conducting field research...
两个站里的科学家还会相互研究
scientists at both stations also study each other...
作为他们所谓的人性因素的一部分
as part ofwhat they call human factors.
人性因素研究
The human factors research...
着眼于人与计算机的互动
looks at the interactions between humans and computers...
人与环境的互动
the interactions between humans and their environment...
以及人与人之间的互动
and with each other.
通过了解我们在不同环境下
By learning howwe're going to react...
相互之间的反应
with each other in different situations...
我们就能够掌握航天员们如何相互影响
we can then learn how crew will react together...
前往火星或呆在火星上
on the way to Mars or on the surface of Mars.
很多发现听上去很明显
A lot of our findings sound very obvious...
但之前确实没有重视过
but they have not really been paid attention to before.
比如 你一开始就会了解到这个活动
For example, the very first thing you learn is that this activity...
穿着宇航服的实地探索是一项体力活动
a field exploration while wearing a spacesuit, is a physical activity.
探索的量完全取决于你的身体状况
The amount of exploration...is very much contingent upon your physical fitness.
这话什么意思呢？
So what is this saying?
就是说 你真想做成什么的话
lt's saying you don't want to go to Mars in zero-gravity...
是不会想在失重状况下去火星的
if you want to actually get anything done...
因为你会受不了的
because you'd be deconditioned.
另一个重要的发现是确定
Another key finding was determining...
人类生存所需要的最低供水量
how little water humans need to survive.
与常人平时每天用上125加仑相比
lt's a drop in the bucket...
真是杯水车薪
compared to the 125 gallons a day the average person uses.
我们已经发现通过仔细配给
We have found that with careful rationing...
通过合适的宇航员 我们就能够限定用水
and with the right kind of crew, we can limit water use...
到每人每天3加仑
down to about three gallons a day per person...
每两天擦一次浴
taking sponge baths every other day...
替代每天的淋浴 仔细地分配
instead of showers every day, and carefully rationing it.
但是 我们如果还想大大降低用水量的话
But if we try to cut the water down much below that...
那么事实上确实会严重影响到士气
then it does in fact start interfering with morale in a serious way.
这是需要掌握的非同小可的数字
And this is a very important number to know...
根据设计任务的工程师的观点
from the point ofview of the engineer designing the mission...
你究竟需要带上多少东西
and how much mass you need to ship.
火星协会把北极和沙漠研究站得到的数据
The Mars Society shares data...
与航天局分享
from its Arctic and desert research stations with NASA.
航天局会研究这些成果
The space agency will study the findings...
因为 他们计划未来在火星上能站稳脚跟
as it plans a future base on Mars...
下一步就是殖民这颗星球
the next step to colonizing the planet.
太空中再见
See you soon in space.
时间:2040年
The year is 2040...
目的地:火星
the destination: Mars.
经过了几十年的仔细研究探讨
After decades of careful study and research...
首批人类探险队正前往红色星球
the first human explorers are on theirway to the Red Planet.
从地球出发 经过整整6个月的行程
After completing the six-month journey from Earth...
史上最长的载人太空之旅
the longest manned space trip in history...
到了登陆火星的时候了
it's time to land on Mars.
然而 最佳着陆点在哪里呢？
But where's the best place to touch down?
你想要地质多样的地方
You want areas that are geologically diverse...
在一个不大的活动半径里
where there's a lot of different things to explore...
有各种各样的东西可以探索
within a reasonably small radius of action.
你肯定想那里包括了
You want to definitely include areas...
过去有过水
that have had water in them in the past...
因为那里可能存在过生命
because that is where there could have been life on the surface.
那是你搜寻生命的地方
That's where you want to hunt for life.
你要到的地方
You want to go to places...
不是温带就是热带
that are either in the temperate or tropical regions of the planet...
因为 你不会去12个月里终日不见阳光的地方
because you don't want to go to a place...where it's going to be dark for twelve months at a time.
按照这些标准 最佳登陆点
By these criteria, the best place to land...
就只有水手谷北部了
would be just north ofValles Marineris...
在径流区的范围内
within driving range of run-off areas...
空间探测器探路者和海盗1号登陆点不远的地方
not far from where space probes Pathfinder and Viking l touched down.
那也是建立营地最佳的地方
lt's also the best place to establish a base camp...
其作用非常像地球上荒野里的营地
that will function much like one in the wilderness on Earth.
在这一望无际的荒漠里 我们可以建起营地
Here in a remote wilderness area, we can establish a base camp...
因为我们拥有所需的一切
because we have everything we need.
我们同样依赖于环境
We also rely on the environment.
我们从环境中获得氧气
We get oxygen from the environment.
获得水
We get water.
从环境中获得去生火的木头
We get wood for fire from the environment.
现在 让我们来想象一下殖民火星
Well, now, let's imagine colonizing Mars.
在火星上 我们同样依赖环境
On Mars, we also rely on the environment.
殖民火星将需要利用火星大气层里
Colonizing Mars is going to require...using the oxygen from the Mars atmosphere...
从二氧化碳中提取的氧气
that we could derive from the carbon dioxide...
在火星上种植粮食
growing food on Mars...
并从火星的大气中获得水
getting water from the atmosphere on Mars.
同样环境中的资源与我们带去的物质组合起来
The same mix of resources from the environment...and material that we brought with us...
也是让我们成功殖民太空所必需的
is what's required to allow us to successfully colonize space.
一旦基地建立起来
Once the base has been established...
早期任务的首要目标
the primary objective of early missions...
就是寻找过去和现在的生命迹象
is to search for evidence of life in the past and the present.
利用雷达宇航员会尝试寻找
Using radar, astronauts attempt to locate groundwater...
地下数百码以下的地下水
within a few hundred yards of the surface...
然后 用钻机将水打上来
then bring it up with drilling rigs.
样本会在居住地的显微镜下进行研究
Samples will be studied under microscopes in the crew habitat...
来观察其中是否具有生命迹象
to see if they contain evidence of life.
一旦星球被证明能够维持生命
lf the planet proves capable of supporting life...
于是宇航员就可以构建温室
then it would be viable for astronauts to construct greenhouses...
种植植物 用上火星上的水 土壤以及阳光
and cultivate crops, using Martian water, soil, and sunlight.
在搜寻生命期间 这些拓荒宇航员
As they search for life, these pioneering astronauts...
将不得不应对一种力
will have to contend with the one force...
会将殖民火星的雄心壮志拉回地球的力
that could bring the lofty ambition to colonize Mars back down to Earth.
那就是重力
That's gravity.
火星上的重力只有地球的三分之一
The gravity on Mars is one-third the gravity on Earth.
我们不知道是否有足够的重力
We don't know if that's enough gravity...
来保证骨骼和肌肉的健康
to allowfor healthy bones and muscles.
如果火星的重力不能保证人类的长期生存
lf Mars' gravity is not suitable for humans' long-term survival...
那它就可能会成为我们的观光之地
it may become the place we visit.
我们可以在那里呆上个把星期
We may go there for a week or so.
只是一个观光点 而不是久留之地
lt's a tourist attraction, but it's not a home.
所以 那是我们需要解决的根本问题
So that's a fundamental question that needs to be answered.
三分之一的重力是否足以让我们在生物学角度达到宜居呢？
ls one-third gravity enough gravity for us to live biologically fit lives?
我猜想答案是可以的
My guess is the answer is yes.
但是我们尚无一手资料 我们只能猜测
But we have no direct data, so we can only guess.
休斯顿 发现号和阿尔法号
Houston, Discovery and Alpha.
对接成功
Capture confirmed.
获得一手资料将是至关重要的
Getting direct data will be vitally important.
因此 会传回地球
So will communicating it to Earth.
火星宇航员与任务控制中心
The lag time in radio communication...
之间的无线电通讯的时间延迟
between the Mars crew and mission control...
会有40分钟 取决于行星之间的距离
as much forty minutes, depending on planetary alignments...
将会影响到宇航员进行的研究
will affect how the astronauts conduct their research.
这确实意味着火星宇航员
lt certainly means that the Mars crew...
其独立性必须远甚于
is going to have to be a lot more autonomous...
地球轨道或月球上的宇航员
than you could have with human crews...in Earth orbit or on the Moon.
你不会和火星宇航员这样交流:
You're not going to be talking to the Mars crew...
现在往左两步 对着石头
"Okay, now step two steps to the left and head towards the rock."
他们将不得不自作主张
They are going to have to make their own decisions.
我认为 更为普遍的是
And l think, more generally...
火星任务肯定是在一线指挥
the Mars mission is going to have to be led from the front...
火星任务的指挥官将直接参与任务
and that the commander of the Mars mission...will be in the Mars mission...
而不是在地球上进行任务支持的任务控制中心
and rather than have mission control...we will have mission support on Earth.
祝大家好运 回去工作吧
Good luck. Back to work now.
回去工作吧 各位
Back to work, all you guys.
宇航员的居所提供了构造的预演
The habitat that will house the astronauts...offers a preview of structures...
它可以组成火星上的第一批定居地
that could form the first settlement on Mars.
火星协会的指导方案中提出
As proposed in the Mars Society's Direct Plan...
最早的居所就是宇航员座舱本身
the initial habitat will be the crew vehicle itself.
"金枪鱼罐" 提出者的叫法
The "tuna can," as its proponents call it...
约20英尺高 直径27英尺
is about twenty feet tall and twenty-seven feet in diameter.
它有两层
lt has two decks...
上层为驾驶舱和共享空间
the upper level for cabins and a common area...
下层为实验室和工作区
the lower one for lab and workspace.
我要走出登月舱了
Okay, l'm going to step off the LEM.
我们发现在实地作业时
We have found in ourfieldwork...
虽然 这些住所比多数美国人平时的
that, while these are tighter quarters...
工作 居住的地方紧凑得多
than mostAmericans are used to working, living in...
但是并不是很糟糕
they're not that bad.
你其实并不感觉到拥挤
You don't really feel that crowded.
我们倾向于把个人床位做得很小
We tend to keep the private bunks very small...
这样我们就能够将公共空间做得最大
so that we can maximize the public space, you know...
起居室是人们常呆的地方
the wardroom where people hang out.
假如你有个健康的乘务组
lfyou've got a healthy crew...
大家都希望相互交流
where the people want to associate with each other...
那么显然 这就是可用空间最佳分配办法
then this is clearly the best way to ration the available space.
随着日益增多的先驱者定居火星有可能较为安全的是
As more pioneers settle on Mars, it may be safer...
将日益增大的社区移至地下
to move the growing community underground.
因为那里是个非常危险的地方
Because it's a terribly dangerous place.
沙尘暴会掀翻任何地面建筑
There are sandstorms that can hit and knock over...any surface establishment.
有可怕的宇宙紫外线的影响
There's horrible ultraviolet cosmic-ray effects.
你会想到挽救人们的生命
You're going to want to save people's lives...
挽救他们的生殖能力
save their reproductive abilities.
你会想到有个地方 可以生儿育女
You're going to want to have a place where you could raise children.
你在火星表面是无法做到的
You're not going to do that at the Martian surface.
你可以在地下做到
You're going to be doing that underground.
在这种环境下
Under those circumstances...
它更像是庞大的城市广场
it would be more like vast urban malls...
或许 非常明亮 用上了核能和太阳能
probably very nicely lit, nuclear and solar power.
生活应该不会很可怕的
lt shouldn't be a terrible life...
只要他们能越过技术上的临界点
providing that they get to a tipping point in technology...
获得外部世界支持的临界点
a tipping point in support from the outside world.
早期前往火星
Early missions to Mars...
如果是在最佳行星距离上进行
if conducted during optimal planetary alignment...
将要持续约2.5年时间
will last approximately two and a halfyears.
其中包括了6个月去的时间
That includes the six months to get there...
一年半呆在上面的时间
a year-and-a-half stay on the surface...
以及6个月回地球的时间
and the six-month return trip to Earth.
期间 我们将会知道火星是否能维系生命
During that time, we will know whether Mars can support life.
可以的话那就打开了殖民的最终形式的大门
lf it can, that opens the door to the ultimate form of colonization...
将其地球化得更像地球
terraforming the planet to make it more like the Earth.
一旦在火星上建立起自给自足的基地
Once humans establish a self-sufficient base on Mars...
那么 下一个太空殖民的主要步骤
the next major advance in space colonization...
按倡导者的说法 将会是地球化这个星球
say advocates, will be to terraform the planet...
也就是将火星更像地球的过程
a process that will make Mars Earth-like.
只要人类定居
Wherever humans have settled...
他们都将改造环境以满足自己的需要
they've remade the environment to suit their needs.
火星也不例外
Mars may not be any different.
地球化或许是根本之道
Terraforming is perhaps the ultimate way...
以创造外太空的新的伊甸园
to create a new Garden of Eden in outer space.
如何做到呢？
And howwould we do it?
来看一下火星
Take a look at Mars.
火星是个荒漠之地
Mars is a frozen desert.
首先 我们会提高其温度
First, we would have to raise the temperature.
我们知道如何来加温星球
We know how to warm up planets.
我们现在就在地球上做这个 在这里不是什么好事
We're doing it right here on Earth, where it's not a good thing...
然而到了火星上 那却是件好事
whereas on Mars, it would be a good thing.
所以 事实上 我们会做与地球上一样的事情
So, in fact, we could do the same things we're doing on Earth...
将温室气体放入大气层
putting in the atmosphere greenhouse gases...
这样就会造成星球变暖
which would cause the planet to warm.
在地球上那可是污染
On Earth, that would be pollution.
而在火星上那可是对症下药
On Mars, it's medicine.
计算表明 我们需要给火星的
Calculations have shown that the amount of greenhouse gases...
温室气体的量是适度的
that we need to introduce to Mars are reasonable.
它们并不会超出我们想象的生产量
They're not really way beyond what we can imagine to produce.
但是 这个量也是非常之大
But the amount is also too large...
我们难以将其从地球带去火星
for us to bring it from the Earth to Mars.
那就意味着 那些气体也必须在火星上生产
That means that those gases have to be produced on Mars.
我们将需要建造工厂来生产这些气体
We would need to set up factories to produce those gases...
并将其排入环境
and release them into the environment.
那些工厂会结合火星环境中取出的元素
These factories would combine elements...taken from the Martian environment...
将其转换成无毒的氟碳气体
convert them to non-toxic fluorocarbon gases...
并排放到大气层里
and vent them into the atmosphere.
据专家估计 在约100年里
Experts estimate in about a hundred years...
这些温室气体将把一个冰冷 干燥 死寂的星球
these greenhouse gases will have terraformed...
地球化为一个温暖 湿润 生机勃勃的世界
a cold, dry, dead planet into a warm, wet, life-supporting world.
有趣之处在于想象一下火星在百年变暖后的模样
lt's interesting to think about what would Mars look like...after a hundred years of warming.
将会比今天更蓝
lt would be bluer than it is today.
你将会看到大片的水
You'd see large patches ofwater.
你会开始看到小小的绿带
You'd start seeing little fringes of green...
围绕着这些蓝色区域的边缘
around the margins of these blue areas.
随着时间的推移 这种绿色的侵袭
And then with time, this infestation of green...
将会迁移并进入山区
would move away and up and into the mountains.
最后 你将会看到一个蓝绿的世界
And eventually, you'd see a world of blue and green...
残留着红色的小岛
with little islands of red that remain...
几乎就像国家公园保护起来
almost like national parks preserve.
在地球化的第一阶段
Then in the first stages of terraforming...
温度将会上升
the temperature will rise...
同时气压也会上升
and also the atmospheric pressure will rise.
那就意味着 人们出门可以就穿着一身贴身衣服
That will mean that humans will actually be able to go out just in suits...
目的是 重建一点压力并戴上一个空气面罩
in order to re-create some pressure and with an air mask.that really press down on their skin...
那样真的出门更加方便了
And that would really make it much easier to go outside.
那恐怕需要花上一段时间
lt will probably take quite a while...
让火星真的变成这样的地方
for Mars to become really a place like this...
就如这个洛杉矶植物园的温室
where we're in a greenhouse at the Los Angeles Arboretum.
那确实要个过程
lt would definitely take a while...
才能获得这样的伊甸园
before we have such a paradise as this.
但是 我们可以始于最基本的藻类
But we can start from very basic algae...
苔藓 甚至草类
mosses, maybe grasses.
与此同时
While this is going on...
人类自身的基因工程也会展开
genetic engineering of the people themselves...
因此 你的生育
could also be taking place so that you are breeding in...
既可以通过优选自己的后代
either through selection ofyour offspring...
甚至还可以基因操控后几代居民
or possibly even genetic manipulation...
让他们在出入火星表面时减少装备
generations of citizens who need less gear...when they go out on the Martian surface.
他们的皮肤不那么脆弱 来对付紫外线
Their skin is less fragile to the ultraviolet...
对付低密度大气层
to the low-density atmosphere.
最终他们所需要的呼吸器将会越来越少
And, eventually, theyjust need their respirators less and less.
由于大气层的增强
As the atmosphere increases...
他们就能够适应部分大气了
so does their ability to meet the atmosphere halfway.
这将成为真正的火星人的起源了
And these would be the beginnings of the true Martians...
人们实际上可以将这个世界打造成自己的世界了
the people who could actually make this world their own.
航天局本身对地球化行星并不感兴趣
NASA itself is not interested in terraforming planets...
部分是因为这听上去非常地科幻
partly because it sounds very science fiction-y...
但是真正部分是因为涉及了伦理问题
but partly because there are real ethical questions involved.
你将会发现好多人认为
You will find a lot of people who believe...
人类不应该进入太空
that human beings should not go into space...
因为我们只会以我们破坏自己星球的方式
because we will just destroy things...
去破坏东西
in the way that we've destroyed our own planet...
我们需要以科学研究的方式来
and that we need to preserve the Moon and Mars...
保护月球 火星以及其他行星
and the other planets the way they are for scientific investigation.
我们是否应该地球化火星
Whetherwe should terraform Mars...
是一个留待后人去解决的问题
is an issue for future generations to resolve.
那是太空殖民历史长河里的一个遥远的时间点
lt's a very distant point on a space colonization timeline...
可能起步于我们这一代人
that could begin with this generation.
我们或许能够预测的一件事
The one thing that we can probably predict...
是我们会自我审视
is that we will see ourselves...
对于太阳系的其他行星要多于地球
in other places of the solar system than the planet Earth.
太空殖民将通过正常的过程来推动
Space colonization will be driven...
我们看到了在人类的历史上
by the normal processes that we've seen over human history...
人们的扩张从一个地方到另一个地方 跨越边境
of expansion of people from one place to another, across frontiers.
太空是另一种边境
Space is another kind offrontier.
那是技术挑战的前沿
lt's a technologically challenging frontier...
但是 人类贯穿历史一直是足智多谋
but the human species has been extraordinarily resourceful...
人类能够适应
over its history in its ability to adapt...
并克服太空前沿之类的挑战
and to overcome challenges like the frontier of space.
我的儿子或许有朝一日将步老爸的后尘
My son, maybe someday, he'll follow in Dad's footsteps...
我将会非常自豪 知道你已经勇往直前
and l would be awful proud knowing that you blazed the trail.
告诉你他会做到的
And, you know, he can do it.
下一代 谁知道他们会去哪？
The next generation, who knows where they'll be?
太空殖民将成为终极野营之旅
Space colonization will be the ultimate camping trip.
它将会考验我们的设备
lt'll test our equipment...
考验我们的计划 考验我们
it'll test our planning, it'll test us...
然而这将是值得的
but it'll be worth it...
去更好地认识太空
to learn a lot about space...
我们的地球 以及我们自己
about our own Earth, and about ourselves.
无论是发生在火星上还是其他什么地方
Whether it happens on Mars or somewhere else...
乃至超出我们的太阳系
maybe even beyond our solar system...
太空殖民的动力将不只是希望插上一面旗帜
space colonization won't be driven by the desire to plant a flag...
而是一颗种子
but rather a seed.
在未来 当我们注目天堂发问
ln the future, when we gaze into the heavens and ask...
有人在吗？
"ls anybody out there?"
回答将有可能是 "有 是我们"
the answerjust might be, "Yes. lt's us."
部分 是因为 这听上去非常地科幻
partly because it sounds very science fiction-y...